<?xml version="1.0"?>
<script>
  <title>adventure.slax</title>
  <author>curtisstephencall</author>
  <synopsis>
	Colossal Cave Adventure!
  </synopsis>
  <coe>op</coe>
  <type>games</type>

  <description>
    <![CDATA[
jnpr@host1> op adventure | no-more

*************************************************
*             Welcome to ADVENTURE!             *
*  Original development by Willie Crowther.     *
*  Major features added by Don Woods.           *
*  Conversion to BDS C by J. R. Jaeger          *
*  Unix standardization by Jerry D. Pohl.       *
*  Conversion to Junos op script by Curtis Call *
*************************************************
     (Type 'instructions' for instructions)
      (Enter 'restore' to load prior game)

-=|End of road|=-
You are standing at the end of a road before a small brick
building.  Around you is a forest.  A small stream flows out
of the building and down a gully.

--What now?>


Description:
------------
This is a fully functional 350-point version of the classic Colossal Cave Adventure game - written in SLAX as a JUNOS op script.  
The dwarves are there, the dragon is lounging on a rug, the troll is guarding the bridge (and is still scared by the bear).  It 
should be pretty much how you remember it.  I say 'pretty much' because there are multiple versions of Adventure floating around, 
so this version might not have all the rooms or the features that you remember.  But, if you are in the mood to play a game on your 
JUNOS device then give it a try.


Background:
-----------
These links explain the history behind the Adventure game:
A history of 'Adventure': http://www.rickadams.org/adventure/a_history.html
Wikipedia Entry: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colossal_Cave


Unique Contributions:
---------------------
Pay a visit to the "Hill in Road".  There is some poetry being recited you might find amusing.  Also, there is an object in the 
"Bedquilt" room that you will find educational to read.


Game Play Tips:
---------------
To play the game, all you have to do is the following:

   1. Copy: adventure.slax file into your /var/db/scripts/op directory
   2. Configure: set system scripts op file adventure.slax
   3. At CLI prompt enter: op adventure | no-more


General Tips:
-------------
    * Each local JUNOS user can play one game at a time.  If two games are played by the same user account then their data 
      values will corrupt each other.
    * Games are automatically saved after every turn.  To restore the prior game type 'restore'.
    * Always append "| no-more" when running the game.
    * If you want to delete all records of Adventure from the SNMP Utility MIB then type "clear mib" at the game prompt.  
      It will delete all Adventure MIB instances and close the game.


WARNING: Memory Leak
--------------------
    * This game is very susceptible to two script-related memory leaks.  As such, keep it off production devices.  The memory 
      leaks are fixed in the following Junos releases:
      9.6S2 (EX only)
      9.6R3
      10.0R2
      10.1R1
    * Due to the memory leaks, the game will have to be restarted when the script memory nears its maximum (~133M).  Type 
      'quit' to halt the game, restart it, and type 'restore' to return to the halted game.
 
      
Hints:
------
Would you like to see a good map?: http://www.spitenet.com/cave/ 
Want some hints?: http://www.rickadams.org/adventure/d_hints/index.html
How about a walkthrough?: http://www.geocities.com/TimesSquare/Castle/2701/ccwalk0.html


Version Details:
----------------
Minimum JUNOS Version: 9.6
Current Script Version: 1.43
MD5 Checksum: b83ca9dd2c47d51a84d8cf521fb3f71c
SHA-256 Checksum: e425e0373e041713d59b435bdf7e167247730ec102a828fbb70036eb8e6361ac
]]>
  </description>
  <keyword>game</keyword>
  <keyword>slax</keyword>
  <keyword>adventure</keyword>

  <xhtml:script xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                src="../../../../../web/leaf.js" 
	        type="text/javascript"/>
</script>
