<?xml version="1.0"?>
<script>
  <title>eol-scanner.slax</title>
  <author>curtisstephencall</author>
  <synopsis>
	Reports EOL status for chassis components and JUNOS version.
  </synopsis>
  <coe>event</coe>
  <type>support</type>

  <description>
    <![CDATA[
 This script scans the installed hardware components and reports if they are on
 the EOL list.  It also checks the current JUNOS version against the JUNOS EOL
 list and reports its status.
 
 To perform chassis scans, copy and enable eol-scanner.slax as an op-script:
 1. Copy to /var/db/scripts/op
 2. Enable via set system scripts op file eol-scanner.slax
 
 Then execute in the following manner:
 user@junos> op eol-scanner
 
 This script can also be run as an event script in JUNOS 9.3 and above by
 following these instructions:
 1. Copy to /var/db/scripts/event
 2. Enable via set event-options event-script file eol-scanner.slax
  
 When run as an event script, every time a FRU is inserted the part will be 
 checked against the EOL list.  A syslog message will be logged if the part 
 appears on the list:
 
 Oct  5 15:47:39  host cscript: New FRU: 710-009178 'M320 FPC Type 3' is on EOL list with status: No warranty conversion
 
 Also, when run as an event script in JUNOS 9.4 and above the software support
 status will be logged to the syslog at every reboot:
 
 Oct  6 06:52:07  host cscript: JUNOS version 9.6 support status: Active engineering support
 
 Caveats:
 - Integrated FPC + PIC cards may not display correctly.
 - Not all FRUs will be checked by the event script
 
 If the script does not report the EOL components of your chassis correctly then
 please email the following two outputs:
 show chassis hardware | display xml
 op eol-scanner
 (Contact information can be retrieved by clicking on the upper-right link).
 
 Minimum JUNOS Version: 8.2 (Unofficially, late revisions of 7.6-8.1 should work as well)
 Minimum JUNOS Version: 9.3 (As an event script)
 Latest Script Version: 1.0
 MD5 Checksum: 6088db00621c255ff946d7a9b9fbd96e
 SHA-256 Checksum: 2d2fe50949cb735b81daa7436125ac45858cd795b1e67457432277e7577ce8ae
]]>
  </description>
  <keyword>support</keyword>
  <keyword>slax</keyword>
  <keyword>eol</keyword>

  <xhtml:script xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                src="../../../../../web/leaf.js" 
	        type="text/javascript"/>
</script>
