<?xml version="1.0"?>
<script>
  <title>revcheck.slax</title>
  <author>mwiget</author>
  <synopsis>
	Enable/Disable the revocation-check based on reachability of the CRL URL
  </synopsis>
  <coe>event</coe>
  <type>security</type>

  <description>
This event script runs every five minutes to checks the reachability
of the CRL URL and disables the CRL command upon unreachability and
reenables it when the CRL server is reachable again via HTTP.

The event script reads the url to check from the security pki ca-profile,
as seen in the following example:

set security pki ca-profile insta revocation-check disable
set security pki ca-profile insta revocation-check crl url "http://10.108.191.86:8080/crl-as-der/currentcrl-31.crl?id=31"

There is usually only one ca-profile configured on a device, so the script
looks for the first occurance and uses it.

Place this script in /var/db/scripts/event on the device and activate
it with the following configuration statement:

set event-options event-script file revcheck.slax

If status doesn't change, then an external info message is sent to syslog
If status changes, an external notice message is written.

To get a message every time the script runs, use the following settings:
set system syslog file messages external info

If only changes shall be documented, use:
set system syslog file messages external notice

Example log messages of disabling the profile 'insta' at 07:15:51 and enabling
it again at 07:40:52:

Oct  6 07:03:16  srx240 cscript: revocation-check remains disabled for ca-profileinsta
Oct  6 07:15:51  srx240 cscript: disable revocation-check for ca-profile insta
Oct  6 07:20:51  srx240 cscript: revocation-check remains disabled for ca-profile insta
Oct  6 07:25:52  srx240 cscript: revocation-check remains disabled for ca-profile insta
Oct  6 07:30:51  srx240 cscript: revocation-check remains disabled for ca-profile insta
Oct  6 07:35:52  srx240 cscript: revocation-check remains disabled for ca-profile insta
Oct  6 07:40:52  srx240 cscript: enable revocation-check for ca-profile insta
Oct  6 07:45:53  srx240 cscript: revocation-check remains active for ca-profile insta

  </description>

  <keyword>SRX</keyword>
  <keyword>pki</keyword>
  <keyword>ca-profile</keyword>
  <keyword>url</keyword>
  <example>
    <title>Example log messages of disabling the profile 'insta' at 07:15:51 and enabling it again at 07:40:52</title>
    <description>syslog events</description>
    <config>example-1.conf</config>
  </example>

  <xhtml:script xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
                src="../../../../../web/leaf.js" 
	        type="text/javascript"/>
</script>
